Guide to the Turkish Photography Collection 1910-1990 AD.MC.007
AbuDhabi
- A male holding a snow ball and two females by his side., 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Snow
- A male and two females standing behind a water pump. Turkish writing in green ink., 19 May 1972 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  Group Portraits; Nature; Photographic Prints
- A mixed group standing in front of a large statue of a military officer. Konya., 1926 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  Group Portraits; Military; Photographic Prints; Statues; Uniforms
- An older couple dancing with a lighted pillar in the background. Foto Bayburt., undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Two women in white coats holding medical equipment., 29 August 1958 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  Coats; Medicine; Photographic Prints; Women
- A group of four men and one woman in a lab coat in a parking lot in front of a large building., 1977-78 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  Coats; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints
- Four females on the front porch of a house, Corlu, Tekirdag. Date in red ink on reverse., 20 May 1973 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Women
- A group of people in summer wear sitting under the shade of a large tree., 1962 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- A bride and groom, groom is wearing a turtle neck. Turkish writing in blue ink on reverse., undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  Couple; Photographic Prints; Wedding Ceremony
- Three females in winter coats standing in front of three large trees. Turkish writing in black ink on reverse., 5 July 1933 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  Group Portraits; Nature; Photographic Prints; Women
- A group of five men standing in front of the Izmir Kulturpark with Turkish flags on the top. Turkish writing on the back in pencil., 21 August 1937 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  Group Portraits; Izmir, Turkey; Men; Parks; Photographic Prints
- A female in a flower patterned dress sitting in front of a painted backdrop. Foto H. Behcet, Konya, Turkey., 26 May 1963 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Two females in dresses standing in front of a trellis on the wall of a building. Turkish writing in blue ink on reverse., 14 July 1941 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- A young male laying in bed with a paper crown on his head at his circumcision ceremony. Turkish writing in blue ink on reverse., 18 August 1964 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  Boys; Ceremony; Circumcisions; Individual Portrait; Photographic Prints
- A female in a winter coat sitting on a stone wall in front of a small wooden building. Ottoman writing on the back in pencil., undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  Coats; Individual Portrait; Ottoman Writing; Photographic Prints; Women
- A family group of six, two young girls are being held by a young woman sitting on a chair. Foto Hilâl, Bakirkoy, Turkey., undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  Children; Family; Family Portraits; Girls; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
- A couple, female in a long silky dress, male in a striped suit. Turkish writing in pencil on the back., 8 October 1959 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  Couple; Photographic Prints; Suits
- A female in a long black dress with short wavy hair. Ottoman writing on the back in pencil., 1931 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  Individual Portrait; Ottoman Writing; Photographic Prints; Women
- A couple, female in a tea length dress, male in a dark double breasted suit. Turkish writing on the back in black ink., 15 September 1946 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- A couple, both in dark suits. Turkish writing in red pencil on the back., 4 March 1926 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- A family group of four, older male seated in a chair. Foto Sen. Ottoman writing in pencil on the back., 1941 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  Family Portraits; Ottoman Writing; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
- A white L-shaped building surrounded by trees and flower beds. Ottoman writing on the back in blue ink., 1955 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  Architecture; Ottoman Writing; Photographic Prints
- A couple, female is wearing a light dress holding a large flower bouquet. Foto Film, Izmir, Turkey., undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Three males in suits sitting on a park bench with some buildings in the background. Ottoman writing in black ink on reverse., 1929 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  Group Portraits; Men; Ottoman Writing; Parks; Photographic Prints
- A family group of four, older male is holding the hand of the younger male in the center. Turkish writing in black ink., 1 December 1942 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- A young male in a three piece suit, with a bow at the collar and a mustache. French writing on the back in French., February 1926 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  Bow Tie; French Writing; Individual Portrait; Mustaches; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits
- Seven males in military uniform in an ever green tree in the countryside. Turkish writing on the back in pencil., undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  Countryside; Group Portraits; Men; Military; Photographic Prints; Uniforms
- A young male in a sailor's outfit. Child's writing in Turkish on the back in pencil., undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  Boys; Children; Individual Portrait; Maritime Outfit; Photographic Prints
- A man in a suit kneeling on the floor with his arms raised above his head. Foto Senel, Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey., 9 April 1961 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Individual Portrait; Men; Photographic Prints
- A baby in a white onesy, in a highchair. Photo Porst. Turkish writing in blue ink., 21 August 1968 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  Children; Individual Portrait; Photographic Prints
- Profile of an older male in a suit. Studio Lale, Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey. Turkish writing in black ink., undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Individual Portrait; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits
- Four males standing in front of a building with a barred window. Turkish writing in black ink., 12 September 1971 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  Group Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Streets
- A young male and female standing in front of a bush and a woman seated on a bench. Turkish writing in black ink on front and back., 1 December 1951 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  Children; Parks; Photographic Prints
- A family group of four, older male is seated, holding the youngest males hand. Foto Istanbul, Karaköy, Istanbul, Turkey., undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  Family Portraits; Foto Istanbul; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
- A couple, female in a light satin dress with a large flower arrangement next to them. Foto Park, Izmir, Turkey. Turkish writing in blue ink., 3 February 1952 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  Couple; Foto Park, Izmir, Turkey; Izmir, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
- A female in a short patterned dress, standing on a small platform with musicians in the background. Foto Raca, Eskisehir, Turkey., 20 May 1961 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  Foto Raca; Gatherings; Individual Portrait; Music; Party; Photographic Prints
- A family group with two younger males flanking an older couple. Foto Ihsan, Kasimpasa, Turkey., undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  Family; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints
- A female in a striped dress and hat with a flower on it., undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  Foto Raca; Gatherings; Hats; Individual Portrait; Party; Photographic Prints; Women
- A family group of four, older female in a skirt suit is seated on a chair. Foto Kamer, Tekirdag., undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  Family Portraits; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits
- Two young males seated on a tree stump. Turkish writing in black in on reverse., 3 March 1936 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  Boys; Children; Nature; Photographic Prints; Suits
- Three females in skirt suits standing in a grass field with trees in the background. Turkish writing on the back in black ink., 7 May 1939 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  Group Portraits; Nature; Photographic Prints; Suits; Women
- A couple, female is seated on a chair with a large updo. Foto Milano, Cubuklu, Istanbul, 4 January 1971 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- A mustached man in a three piece suit with tie and a pinky ring on his right hand. Turkish writing in blue ink., 1928 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- An older female with a head scarf and a young child standing on a chair. Ottoman writing on the back in pencil., undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  Children; Ottoman Writing; Photographic Prints; Streets; Women
- A young female squatting to pick bananas. Turkish writing in blue ink on the back., undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
- A family group standing on a gravel drive way with tall hedges in the background. Turkish writing in black ink on reverse. Foto Park. Izmir., 22 November 1949 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  Family; Foto Park, Izmir, Turkey; Izmir, Turkey; Parks; Photographic Prints
- A young male in a three piece suit holding a book, leaning on a pedestal. Turkish writing in black ink., 6 Novemeber 1937 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  Individual Portrait; Men; Photographic Prints; Suits
- A family group of four, a couple is seated on chairs in front of two females., 11 June 1954 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  Couple; Family Portraits; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
- A woman in a flower patterned dress, holding a small baby in a dress and cap on her lap. Foto Yildiz, Oskodar. Turkish writing in black ink on reverse., 5 September 1936 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  Children; Foto Yildiz; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Women
- A young couple, female in a light patterned dress, male holding her arm in a suit. Turkish writing in blue ink on reverse., 1959 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- A bride seated in a chair with a male sitting beside her, white curtains in the background. Foto Fehmi, Antalya, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  Antalya, Turkey; Couple; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Wedding Portraits
- A young male in military uniform. Turk Fotograf. Turkish writing on the front and back in black ink., 16 February 1934 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  Individual Portrait; Military; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Uniforms
- A young male in military uniorm. Foto Galatasaray, Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey., undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Individual Portrait; Military; Photographic Prints; Uniforms
- A young female with short hair and a dark dress turning to face the camera. Turkish writing in black ink., 5 March 1933 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- A couple, female is wearing a long light dress holding a large bouquet of flowers, male is holding her arm. Ar Foto, Uskudar, Turkey., undated (Bin 6, Folder 10)
- A couple, female is wearing a white lace ballgown with gloves, male is in a suit holding her arm. Foto Sen. Turkish writing in green ink., 20 June 1953 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- A young couple, female is in a long sleeved wedding dress, groom is in military uniform. Foto Bayezi. Turkish writing on the back in black ink., 21 September 1948 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  Couple; Military; Photographic Prints; Uniforms; Wedding Portraits
- A bride and groom seated facing each other looking at the camera with flower arrangements. Studio Tuncer. Turkish writing in blue ink on reverse., 13 May 1977 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- A bride with a lace dress and a puffy veil wearing glasses, male in a suit standing next to her. Turkish writing in blue ink., undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  Couple; Eye Glasses & Sunglasses; Photographic Prints; Wedding Ceremony
- A bride in a large ballgown and tiara, sitting on a couch with a male in a suit. Foto Raca, Eskisehir, Turkey., 9 June 1962 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  Couple; Jewelry; Photographic Prints; Wedding Portraits
- A bride and groom walking down a flight of stairs with guests looking on. Turkish writing in black ink on reverse., 29 August 1975 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- A bride standing in front of a mirror with a small girl holding a large bouquet of flowers. Foto Lüks., undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  Children; Photographic Prints; Wedding Ceremony; Women
- A bride seated in a chair with a male in a dark suit holding her shoulders. Studio Almaco, Izmir, Turkey. Turkish writing in blue ink., 15 February 1961 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  Couple; Izmir, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Wedding Portraits
- A light haired bride standing with a male in a tuxedo. Turkish writing in blue ink., 6 April 1959 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Three males in military uniform relaxing on a bench. Turkish writing in blue ink., undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  Men; Military; Photographic Prints; Uniforms
- A male in military unform holding a gun in his belt, standing in front of a backdrop with pink and yellow overpainted flowers. Turkish writing in blue ink, Ottoman writing in pencil., 2 July 1944 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  Guns; Handtinting; Individual Portrait; Military; Ottoman Writing; Photographic Prints; Turkish Writing; Uniforms
- A family group of four, two young females are wearing the same dress. Foto Sik, Lefkosa. Turkish writing in blue ink., 16 June 1961 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- A bride in a frilly trimmed dress, seated with the groom standing next to her. Fotograf Studyosu Istanbul. Blue stamp on the back., undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  Couple; Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Wedding Portraits
- A bride and groom seated on two chairs with a large flower bouquet across their laps, an older couple stands behind them. Ressam Foto., undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  Couple; Family; Photographic Prints; Wedding Portraits
- A bride with a long veil holding onto white trelis with a male in a suit standing behind her. Foto Serengil. Turkish writing in blue ink., undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
- A bride seated on a chair looking up at the groom. Turkish writing in blue ink on reverse., 30 July 1966 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  Couple; Photographic Prints; Wedding Portraits
- Four males sitting on a picnic blanket eating and drinking with a tree in the background., undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  Drinking; Eating; Group Portraits; Men; Nature; Photographic Prints
- A young couple, female in a short sparkly dress, male in a suit standing behind her holding her arm. Saray Fotograf Studyosu. Turkish writing in blue ink., undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  Couple; Foto Saray; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits
- A female with short curly hair and dark lipstick sitting in an armchair. Foto Turan, Istanbul, Turkey., 1951 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- A female in a black v-neck dress with pearl necklace, resting her arm on a large chair. Foto Saray, Istanbul. Turkish writing in black ink., 19 March 1961 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  Foto Saray; Individual Portrait; Istanbul, Turkey; Jewelry; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Women
- An older male in a three piece suit with a mustache. Ottoman writing on the back in pencil., 17 November 1926 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  Individual Portrait; Ottoman Writing; Photographic Prints; Suits
- A family group four, with two females holding a baby in their laps and a young male standing behind them. Turkish writing in pencil on back., 6 February 1952 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- A young girl with a short haircut, wearing an outfit with little stars on it. Studio Sabah, Beyoglu, Istanbul., 15 May 1958 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Children; Foto Sabah; Individual Portrait; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
- A family group of five, young female in front with a large white bow and a checkered dress sitting on a stool. Turkish writing in black ink., 16 May 1942 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Two young females in dresses, both wearing white knee-high socks. Turkish writing in purple pencil., undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
- An older female in a skirt suit and glasses, standing with a young girl in a light dress and hat. Bizim Foto, Kütahya., undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  Eye Glasses & Sunglasses; Girls; Hats; Photographic Prints; Suits
- A young female standing on a stool, wearing a dress with small flowers on the collar and sleeve and a hat. Foto Safak-Rize, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
- A young male in a three piece suit, resting his hand on a table. Sutdio name in Cyrillic script. Turkish writing in pencil on the back. Photo is cut in half., 21 February 1934 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  Individual Portrait; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits
- A family group of four standing on a carpet, young girl in a black dress with white braided pattern and large white bow in her hair. Ottoman writing in black ink on reverse., undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  Children; Family Portraits; Photographic Prints; Suits
- A couple, female in a black dress with a large bow at the neck, male is in a military uniform. Foto Ferit Ibrahim, Istanbul, Turkey. Turkish writing in blue ink on reverse., 3 March 1937 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  Couple; Military; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Uniforms
- A young girl in a dress and white knee high socks standing on a wooden chair. Ottoman writing in black ink on back., 1943 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- A female with a short cut with bangs and cat eye liner. Studyo Esmer, Balikesir., undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
- A young girl in a black dress, with a polka dot sash on her waist and a large bow in her hair standing in front of painted backdrop and a small bust. Turkish writing in pencil., undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
- A small baby sitting on a chair cover in a striped cloth. Ottoman writing in purple ink., undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  Children; Individual Portrait; Ottoman Writing; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
- A head shot of a female in a white collared shirt with curly hair and fake eyelashes. Studyo Yasar, Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey., undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Cihangir, Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Individual Portrait; Makeup; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
- Three children, older girl is wearing a striped shirt. Cinar Fotograf Studyosu., undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
- An older male seated in a chair, wearing a tuxedo, holding a cigarette, with a painted backdrop in the background. Foto Artistik, Sisli-Osmanbey., undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  Cigarettes; Individual Portrait; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits
- A young male in a white outfit with stripped collar and cuff. Foto Dilaver., undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  Boys; Children; Individual Portrait; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
- A small baby in a black outfit with a white hat and a painted backdrop in the background. Turkish writing in black ink., undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  Children; Hats; Individual Portrait; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
- A couple, female in a dark outfit holding a purse, male in a light suit with tie. Ottoman writing on the back in pencil., undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  Couple; Ottoman Writing; Photographic Prints
- A young female child wearing a black dress in a stroller with a painted backdrop in the background., 1934 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- A group of five males in military unform posed outside next to a building. Ottoman writing on the back in purple., 25 February 1927 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  Boys; Group Portraits; Men; Military; Ottoman Writing; Photographic Prints; Uniforms
- A female sitting on the edge of a chair in a light lacey dress, holding the hand of a standing male in black suit. Foto Turan, Istanbul, Turkey., undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  Couple; Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
- A young male in a pin-striped double breasted jacket and white shirt. Grid lines drawn on the front, stamped 10 Temmuz 1941, 10 July 1941 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  Individual Portrait; Photographic Prints; Suits
- A female with her back to the camera, looking off to the right with an updo and white circle earings. Turkish writing in blue ink on the reverse., 30 June 1958 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  Individual Portrait; Makeup; Photographic Prints; Women
- A young female with long braids, sitting behind two wooden chairs. Ottoman writing on the back in pencil., undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  Individual Portrait; Ottoman Writing; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
- A couple, female in a dark dress seated in a chair with male in double breasted suit standing next to her on a carpet. Turkish writing in black ink., 23 August 1934 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- A female in a nun's habit. Turkish writing in black on reverse. Studio Bilsen, 21 March 1956 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  Individual Portrait; Nuns; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
- A family group of three with the young male wearing the traditional circumcision cap and sash. Turkish writing in black ink on the reverse., undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  Circumcisions; Family Portraits; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
- An older male with a moustache and glasses, wearing a robe and holding a diploma, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  Education; Eye Glasses & Sunglasses; Individual Portrait; Mustaches; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
- A family group of three females, wearing head scarves and three small children., 30 August 1944 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  Children; Family Portraits; Photographic Prints; Women
- Two older females holding a younger female with a large white bow on her head. Foto Fenni, Antalya, Turkey. Turkish writing in blue ink on reverse., undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  Antalya, Turkey; Family Portraits; Girls; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Women
- A family group of four, couple is each holding a young child in front of some bushes with water in the background. Foto Yildiz. Turkish writing on the back in pencil., 16 November 1947 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  Children; Couple; Family; Foto Yildiz; Photographic Prints; Turkish Writing
- A family group of four, baby in the middle is making a funny face. Turkish writing on the back in blue ink., 3 June 1961 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  Children; Family; Photographic Prints; Turkish Writing
- A male in a light suit walking on the street next to a building with barred windows. Foto Estanta, Istanbul. Turkish writing in pencil on back., 18 May 1942 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  Individual Portrait; Istanbul, Turkey; Men; Photographic Prints; Streets; Suits; Turkish Writing
- A female in a dark skirt suit standing in front of Ataturk statue. Writing on the back., 1949 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  Ataturk; Individual Portrait; Photographic Prints; Suits; Women
- An older couple standing in front of some curtains, female is holding a bouquet of flowers wearing a bucket hat. Turkish writing in blue ink on reverse., 10 May 1963 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  Couple; Hats; Photographic Prints; Turkish Writing
- A family group of four, young male is wearing a circumcision outfit. Turkish writing on the back in black ink., 6 June 1976 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  Circumcisions; Family Portraits; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkish Writing
- A group of three young females in short black dress and an older male wearing sunglasses. Foto Yildiz, Eskisehir, Turkey., undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  Foto Yildiz; Girls; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Suits
- A female in a striped shirt holding a baby on her lap while seated in a chair. Turkish writing on the back in pencil., undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
  Family; Photographic Prints; Turkish Writing
- A young girl in a white outfit and hat sitting on a stone ball, next to some stairs. Turkish writing in pencil., undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
  Girls; Hats; Individual Portrait; Photographic Prints; Turkish Writing
- A couple, female is wearing a short lace dress and long white gloves, male is wearing a suit. Turkish writing in blue ink., undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
  Couple; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkish Writing
- A group of four males, two seated on chairs, outside in front of some buildings. Turkish writing in blue ink on reverse., 17 April 1967 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  Group Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Turkish Writing
- Three females cutting a large multi-tiered cake. Foto Engin, Bursa, Turkey., undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
  Bursa, Turkey; Party; Photographic Prints; Women
- A young boy in dark overalls standing in front of some plants and a pool. Turkish writing on the back., undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
  Children; Handtinting; Individual Portrait; Photographic Prints; Turkish Writing
- A family group of nine, seated around a rustic wooden table under a wooden shade. Ottoman writing on the back in pencil., 1925 (Box 6, Folder 17)